Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 4. Australia, 1942-1965; 183 cans
  - Australian Outback, 1944; linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1222)
    Countdown, men digging, men standing on the back of a jeep, man emptying a bucket of water, a large lizard, koala on a tree near a small bird, a group of large two-legged birds, men walking away from a jeep, close up on funny looking rock, men looking at the rocks, jeeps driving up, men walking across rocks, a group of men enter a cave, cave drawings, men walking across rock, a man doing something with sticks, a man digging, three men talking, men walking across rocks, something buried in rocks, men gathered around something, men walking across rocks, man hammering into rock, High Adventure with Lowell Thomas, man hammering something, man climbing rocks, man looking around trees and rocks, man looking at something closely, landscape scenes, 2 Jeeps driving through, men walking through, three men talking, a man walks to a spot and is followed by others, three men talking to a group of men, a couple men digging, three men talking, a few men digging find a skull, one man looking at the skull talks to the men gathered around him, a grave with a head stone saying "Harold B. Lasseter Died 1931", High Adventure With Lowell Thomas, Directed By Lee Robinson, Produced By Lowell Thomas and Lee Robinson, Narration Written By Prosper Buranelli, Photography By Carl Kayser and Robert Wright, Film Editors Gil Margolis, Lillian Jones, and Keith Loon, Supervising Film Editor David Cooper, Color By MovieLab, Rerecording by Al Gramaglia, Sound Recordist Donald Connolly, Production Manager Alton Frazer, Production Assistant Bruce Anderson, Supervisor of Production Milton A. Frachtman, Odyssey Production, High Adventure With Lowell Tomas.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1945; 1868 linear feet 1 2000ft (16mm) (Can 1596)
    Full episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in Ã„ustralia. Directed by Lee Robinson. Prodcued by Lowell Thomas and Lee Robinson. Lowell Thomas travels to the Australian Outback and enlists the help of Aboriginies to figure out what happened to explorer Harold Bell Lasseter 28 years ago. Contains leader where commericals would likely go. Copyright 1958.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australian Outback, 1837 linear feet 1 2000ft (16mm) (Can 1597)
    Full episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in the Arctic. Directed by Bruce Anderson. Produced by Lowell Thomas, Jr. under executive producer Lowell Thomas. Lowell Thomas, Jr. visits a DEW Line radar site. Lowell Thomas, Sir Hubert Wilkins, Burt Balcombe [?], and Donald McMillan visit Eskimos and scientific outposts on their way from Point Barrow, Alaska to the North Pole. Upon their arrival in Greenland, the perils and effectiveness of Arctic air rescue teams are demonstrated.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1945; 1843 linear feet 1 2000ft (16mm) (Can 1598)
    Full episode of "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" in Australia. Directed by Lee Robinson. Prodcued by Lowell Thomas and Lee Robinson. Lowell Thomas travels to the Australian Outback and enlists the help of Aboriginies to figure out what happened to explorer Harold Bell Lasseter 28 years ago. Contains leader where commericals would likely go. Copyright 1958.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - L. Thomas Show 2 Reel 2 Australia Mus. B, 1953; 1419 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1648)
    On the audio track you hear music and instruments being played.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Lowell Thomas Show 2 Reel 2 "Australia" Music, 1953; 1440 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1649)
    Australian Steps of Daneers; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia sound effects, 1370 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1650)
    On the audio track you can hear airplane sounds, birds chirping and you hear people talking in a different language.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1954; 1385 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1651)
    The audio records a car engine, birds, hooves, pouring/rushing water, and a plane.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1738 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1652)
    Lowell Thomas narrates from Australia. He searches for the missing Australian, Harold Lassater. Aboriginal men help him track down Lassater's body in the desert. They have a ceremony dedicated to Harold Lassater.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Capital Cities Lowell Thomas "High Adventure" Theatrical R4 Dialog TRK Sinbad, 1739 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1653)
    On the audio track you hear people talking in another language and you also hear Lowell Thomas talking about the search for spices and the search for cloves. You also hear him talking about the Australian myth called Lasseter.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - High Adventure Theatrical R4, 1739 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1654)
    "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas." Lowell Thomas is on a ship with his crew. They sail towards Zanzibar so they can sell their pearls. Lowell Thomas collects cloves from the clove orchard. Cut to Lowell Thomas in Australia. He meets with Aboriginese men and they show him how they live off the land. They help Lowell track down the body of a missing man (Harold Lassater) in the desert.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - High Adventure Theatrical R4 narration, 1757 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1655)
    Lowell Thomas narrates the last leg of his 6 week and 4,000 mile journey travelling with African merchants in which they bargain for salt in Sheba and sail to Zanzibar to sell their pearls from the Persian gulf. He briefly describes games that are played including Arabian stick ball and bull fighting, introduced by the Portuguese. From there Thomas travels to Alice Springs in the Australian Outback to find Harold Lasseter, a traveler who had disappeared in the desert. He describes the Aborigini lifestyle including their hunting weapons (the boomerang, used to paralyze animals, and spears made from emu thigh bone) and how they find water. In the end of the film they discover a skeleton where a local man said he had seen his people bury Lasseter's body and a doctor confirms Lasseter's identity. A monument for Lasseter is placed in Alice Springs.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 893 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1656)
    Clapboard, people standing around tombstone, Harold B. Lasseter's tombstone, man walking through rocks, man looking around, man walking up hill, man collecting sticks and leaves?, 3 men talking, man looking at rock through magnifying glass, man holding a box, man looking at something in his hands, older man with hat and a mustache, field with trees, 4 men standing, 3 men standing, one man showing three other men something, Harold's tombstone surrounded by rocks in the shape of a cross, man standing near body of water? with box, large pile of rocks, man picking at rock with sharp tool, man examining rock; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1657)
    clapboard, close up of man's face, adult with a tool and a child, man sitting and using a tool, man looking down; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1658)
    man standing outside, shot of stream, close up of man, man in tree, man's hand holding a rock?, man's legs walking through area my stream, shot of brush and trees, medium shot of 3 men; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australian Outback, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1659)
    clapboard in front of a person's face, shot of man's face, clapboard in front of barren trees, barren trees and rocks, two men walking and holding a walking stick, men walking through the dry terrain, men walking by rock mountains, man sitting while surrounded by a group of men, clapboard in front of group of men, group of men standing, man with hat on in corner of frame, rocks, men climbing rocks, jeep hidden behind trees, people in a jeep, jeep with label saying Southern International Control, man sitting and observing a skull, men staring off-camera at something, men walking towards the trees, men standing in a circle; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1660)
    Small house with people in front; cars parked among trees with men walking around; trees and mountains; fleet of trucks driving through field.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1958; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1661)
    Various native peoples; men in front of "Alice Springs Post Office"; hand holding sticks up; natives making a fire, possibly a ritual.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1662)
    hands digging, close up of two boys, clapboard, close up of unidentified object, close up of hands cleaning unidentified object, plack of wood? with "S T 2957" written on it, close up of elderly man with beard, man danding at end of tunnel, shot of building, men standing under structure, long shot of land, truck driving through barren landscape; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australian Outback, 1957; linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1663)
    clapboard, two men talking, man crouching etching a name (Harold), close up of man, man dumping liquid from bucket into funnel, two men riding in back of truck, men filling bag with hose,man drinking from hose; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 1954; 1397 linear feet 1 2000ft (35mm) (Can 1664)
    A High Adventure with Lowell Thomas explores the lives of primitive men and intriguing animals in Australia. Lowell visits the famous landmark Uluru or Ayers rock, which is believed to be the beginning of the world for Australian aborigines. Lowell Thomas takes a team with him to help solve a great Lasseter Mystery.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical; Type: Negative
  - Australia, 547 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2389)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas asks tribal guide several questions about Lasseter and receives answers. This is during the Australia expedition.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 520 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2390)
    Audio Track: Water, trumpet or elephant, wind + other sounds hard to distinguish.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 265 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2391)
    Audio Track: Wind + People talking.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 560 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2392)
    Audio Track: Sound of plane flying and engine starting.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 910 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2393)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas narrating about expedition in Australia. He speaks about rain, water, and the tribal people teaching their children survival skills.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 759 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2394)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas talking to someone about location of water.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Australia sound effects, 173 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2395)
    Audio track: Sounds of various animals; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia music, 944 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2396)
    Music playing, sounds like an orchestra; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical, Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 61 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2397)
    Audio track. Lowell Thomas talking to another man.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 762 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2398)
    One of the guide men pulls up dirt and smells it. All of the guide men dig into the earth with shovels, unveiling water. They fill buckets with water and load them onto the vehicles. Lowell Thomas talks about different animals such as koala bears, iguanas, and emus. One of the guide men shows Lowell Thomas a stone covered in markings. Lowell Thomas asks questions about it. He is then showed a cave before sitting down and talking to one of the guide men about Lasseter.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 859 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2399)
    Tribal man teaches his sons hoe to make fire. A group of tribal men return with kangaroos slung over their shoulders. They cook them. A ritual is performed. In the next scene, a vehicle drives through the desert. A wheel gets stuck but they resolve the issue. Expedition crew briefly stops for a break before continuing. They stop at Ayers Rock and pick up a lizard. They set up camp and Lowell Thomas talks about the species of lizards they encountered. They continue driving, aiming to find water.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1958; 150 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2400)
    Lowell Thomas speaking about the difficulties of the film world, and the difficulties he had while filming real events such as his crew and natives consistently freezing up in front of the camera; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Odyssey- Australia Narration Mag. Trk. Reel 5, 854 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2401)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas narrating about gold, minerals, Lasseter's fate/grave/diary.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia sound effects, 1949; 813 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2402)
    Audio Track: Sound of car; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 320 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2403)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas narrating bits of Australia expedition. He announces the next expedition in India, giving insight on what events will take place.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Kids Laugh--chicken at water hole/kids yell/laugh--giggle/kids voices, 353 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2404)
    Audio Track: Children yelling, laughing. Chicken making noises. Children talking in foreign language. Children laughing again.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1945; 415 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2405)
    Audio Track: Interview being conducted among two men.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1954; 865 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2406)
    Audio Track: Quick "swoosh" noise; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color, N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 614 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2407)
    Sound of claps, knocking, and crumbling.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 869 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2408)
    Man mines rocks. Men clear branches and twigs so vehicles can pass through. They continue driving through the wilderness. The expedition crew speculate where Lasseter's grave could be. The tribal guides say they buried him by a tree with a branding. One of the guides walk up the tree and start hacking at it with a knife. They don't find the branding. One of the tribal guides walk to a specific spot, claiming that's where Lasseter was buried. Lowell Thomas follows him and calls over the rest of the crew. They begin to dig. Lowell Thomas asks a man how they'd be able to tell the body truly belongs to Lasseter.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 787 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2409)
    Lowell Thomas talks about Australia. An airplane flies through the sky. Lowell Thomas talks to the pilot. Shots of different newspaper articles. Lowell Thomas exits the plane. People are preparing to go to Never-Ever-Land Lowell Thomas talks multiple people about the mystery of Never-Ever-Land. Lowell Thomas talks to the camera before pointing to a group of men who use sign language to communicate among themselves. Vehicles drive through the wild. One of the vehicles wheels get stuck in the dirt but the expedition group manages to pull it out.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - (Shmp- Womram- Seed?), 238 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2410)
    Someone walking through mud, rusty machine, sharpening, rock scraping against something; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 860 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2411)
    Audio Track. Narration of expedition in Never-Ever-Land in Australia.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 883 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2412)
    Audio Track. Narration bits about expedition in Never Ever Land and the mystery surrounding it.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia Auto Sound Rev Sand, 354 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2413)
    Audio Track: Engine starting and vehicle driving. Sometimes the sound of the vehicle gets louder as if its getting closer. Someone talks briefly; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia Auto Sound Rev Sand, 353 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2414)
    Car driving, car driving on grass, car getting progressively closer, something that sounded like an explosion, car revving up; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - N,E,S, West Delco Commercial #1, 1957; 320 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2415)
    Vehicles driving through water. Commercial for Delco Battery. Shows footage of different places in the world, showcasing the Delco battery.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 419 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2416)
    Group of men including Lowell Thomas watch several others dig in the dirt with shovels and hands. They discover bones.One of the men dig up a skull and passes it to Lowell Thomas. They all walk towards a stone with engravings on it, surrounded by small rocks. The credits begin.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 904 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2417)
    Men take bags front of truck, fill them with water, and attach them back onto truck. Lowell Thomas talks to man about water and Lasseter's Reef. Shots of water flowing. A Vehicle gets stuck while driving through the water. Another vehicle comes behind it and pushes it through the water and onto land. Vehicles drive through the wilderness. Shots of tribal parents teaching their children necessary skills to survive. Such as, how to throw a boomerang, make different tracks, and how to find water.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 915 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2418)
    Audio Track. Conversation between Lowell Thomas and another man. They're talking about Lasseter expedition mystery. Lowell Thomas announces they found Lasseter's body and solved the mystery about the Australian Bush.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1946; 23 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2419)
    Audio Track: Lowell Thomas gives one sentence narration.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1945; 755 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2420)
    Lowell Thomas narrating events in Australia expedition. Talks about water/rivers, wildlife. tribal men, dreaming time and Lasseter.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1958; 23 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2421)
    "Take 2, 2. Sound 3." Followed by mumbling sound.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 246 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2422)
    Galloping horses, people chanting, machine and digging sounds; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 574 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2423)
    Native singing, people chanting, native drums, low galloping, loud galloping; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Explorer's Reel, 1942; 900 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2424)
    Man narrating about things pertaining to mystery and expedition in Never-Ever -Land; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia Closed Door GWC to Stop and Rover, 1945; 468 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2425)
    Audio Track: Sound of wheels spinning in sand. Vehicle driving and coming to a stop. Person speaking foreign language. Vehicle driving down road. Truck engine starts. Door opening and closing.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 211 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2426)
    Different cuts of title tracks, including credits; Format: 35mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1957; 298 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2427)
    Two different versions of the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas" opening credits.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color, Black & White; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 28 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2428)
    Audio snippet of Lowell Thomas'narration about the desert.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 28 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2429)
    On the audio track you hear someone telling thanks to a primitive man and his instincts.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1954; 361 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2430)
    "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas." Lowell Thomas and crew travel to Australia, hoping to solve the mystery of the missing Harry Lassater. Cut to the "High Adventure with Lowell Thomas," closing credits.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1954; 320 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2431)
    An Aboriginal man finds bullet holes in a tree trunk. Lowell Thomas interviews more Aboriginal men about a criminal.; Format: 35mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 620 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2432)
    On the audio track you can hear birds and other animal sounds; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1967; 101 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2433)
    On the audio track you can hear water sounds, car sounds, other different sounds, car sounds and children yelling.; Format: 35mm; Picture: N/A - Audio track only; Audio: Magnetic; Type: Positive
  - Australia, 1954; 85 linear feet 1 1000ft (35mm) (Can 2434)